A Guide to the Elizabeth Wilkinson letters, 1943-1961
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Elizabeth Wilkinson letters, 1943-1961
The Library of Virginia
53125
1.35 cu. ft. (3 boxes)
Elizabeth Wilkinson
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Purchased.
Biographical Information
Ruth Elizabeth Wilkinson was born 4 March 1922 in Richmond, Virginia, to Herbert W. Wilkinson (1885-1975) and Ruth Watkins Wilkinson (1892-1973). She graduated from Thomas Jefferson High School and worked as a stock assistant and clerk at Thalhimer's. Wilkinson attended Averett College in Danville Virginia, graduating in 1948. She taught school in Buckingham County, Virginia, during the 1948-1949 school year and in Berryville, Clarke County, Virginia, during the 1949-1950 school year. Wilkinson then attended Longwood College in Farmville, Virginia, graduating in 1952. She returned to Richmond to teach, then spent at least a year teaching in Nyack, New York, in 1960-1961. Wilkinson returned to Richmond and taught at Holladay Elementary School in Henrico County, Virginia. Wilkinson died 2 April 1996 in Henrico County and was buried in Westhampton Memorial Park.
Scope and Content
Letters, 1943-1961, to Elizabeth Wilkinson (1922-1996) while attending school at Averett College (Danville, Va.) and Longwood College (Farmville, Va.), and teaching in Buckingham and Clarke Counties, Virginia, and Nyack, New York, mainly from her mother Ruth Watkins Wilkinson (1892-1973) and her sister Helen Judson Wilkinson (1923-2002) of Richmond, Virginia, offering encouragement and support toward her education and career, and providing news of family, friends, and events in Richmond. Letters also include correspondence from Averett College and from the Charles B. Keesee Education Fund regarding loans for school, and correspondence from students she taught in Berryville in Clarke County. Collection also includes birthday cards, Christmas cards, and greeting cards, as well as newspaper clippings.
Contents List
- Letters, 1943-1946 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Letters, February, July-August 1947 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Letters, September 1947 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Letters, October 1947 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Letters, November 1947 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Letters, December 1947 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Letters, January-February 1948 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Letters, March 1948 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Letters, 1-9 April 1948 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Letters, 11-29 April 1948 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Letters, May 1948 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Letters, August-15 September 1948 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Letters, 17-30 September 1948 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Letters, October-November 1948 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Letters, December, no date 1948 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Letters, January-February 1949 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Letters, March 1949 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Letters, April-June 1949 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Letters, September 1949 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Letters, October-November 1949 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Letters, January 1950 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Letters, February 1950 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Letters, March 1950 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Letters, May-August 1950 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Letters, September 1950 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Letters, October 1950 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Letters, November-December 1950 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Letters, January-March 1951 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Letters, April-May 1951 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Letters, September 1951 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Letters, October 1951 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Letters, November-December 1951 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Letters, January 1952 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Letters, February 1952 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Letters, March 1952 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Letters, April 1952 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Letters, June-July 1952 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Letters, December 1952 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Letters, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Letters, August-September 1960 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Letters, October-November 1960; Clippings, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Letters, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Letters, undated (ca. 1947-1952) (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Letters, undated (ca. 1960) (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Cards, undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Clippings, pamphlets, addresses undated (Box 3, Folder 17)